{
    "id": "f642d1f9a5cd433b9dfe2d4cd3beaace",
    "title": "Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Whose bag is this? It is …………………………",
            "description": "Mine is a possessive pronoun it is used alone. My is a possessive adjective. It is followed by a noun.",
            "answers": [
                "my",
                "mine",
                "me"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He patted ………………………. on the back.",
            "description": "When the subject and object refer to the same person, use the reflexive pronoun.",
            "answers": [
                "he",
                "himself",
                "him"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Each one of .............................. narrated their own version of the story.",
            "description": "Use an object pronoun after a preposition. ",
            "answers": [
                "they",
                "them",
                "their"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me what ………………………… problem was.",
            "description": "We use the possessive adjective my to modify the noun problem here. ",
            "answers": [
                "I",
                "me",
                "my"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "That child of ……………………………. has broken my window.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "you",
                "your",
                "yours"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "They elected …………………………. their leader.",
            "description": "A pronoun used as the object of a verb should be in its object form.",
            "answers": [
                "he",
                "him",
                "his"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited for ………………………… but they didn’t come.",
            "description": "A pronoun used as the object of  preposition should be in its object form.",
            "answers": [
                "they",
                "them",
                "their"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She is taller than ……………………………. is.",
            "description": "A pronoun used as the subject of a verb should be in its subject form.",
            "answers": [
                "he",
                "him",
                "his"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t want to go with ………………………………",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "he",
                "him",
                "his"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Be careful or you will injure ……………………………",
            "description": "When the subject and object refer to the same person, use the reflexive pronoun.",
            "answers": [
                "you",
                "yourself",
                "yours"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Please do it ………………………….",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "you",
                "yourself",
                "your"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You are no better than ………………………….",
            "description": "Object pronouns are more common after than and as. ",
            "answers": [
                "he",
                "him",
                "his"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}